Guy Guzman

406 SE Birch Ave Apt 201 College Place, WA 99324

310-946-8410 guy.guzman@gmail.com

Summary

I am a senior level full-stack Microsoft developer and business analyst and have been developing with the .NET framework since 2002.

I have done extensive business process and workflow analysis (25 years). This includes abstracting complex investment structures, business process modelling, business process mapping, workflow redesign and recommendations to the client to improve efficiency.

My core technical strengths are the .NET and .NET Core frameworks (thru .NET 6), Database Architecture, Microsoft SQL Server, C#, Microsoft Azure, Windows WPF, SQL, Restful API, HTML, JavaScript and CSS.

Experience

EasyDMR

Mar 2018 - Jun 2022 (Owner)

Complete design, coding and implementation of an application that tracks food delivery driver's documents and calculates the mileage reimbursement rate. I determined the correct method to calculate a reimbursement rate using factors such as vehicle depreciation, fuel, etc. that is IRS compliant. Efforts including creating a database with every possible vehicle from 1992 forward (year, make, model, trim) which yielded over 40,000 entries. Fuel rates, electrical rates (for EVs) had to be located and then regularly updated in the database. The calculation supports EVs using a MPGe value and conversion to electrical energy (KWh). Franchisee owners create accounts and add their stores. Drivers create their own accounts and upload their documents (normally using the camera on their smart phone). Monthly billing for owners is done via Stripe (SaaS for financial services). Application was designed mobile first.

The application was designed using .NET Core (starting with version 2.2) and is now running .NET 6. It is hosted in Azure and uses Azure SQL Server, Azure Active Directory B2C and supports social logins, Azure Blob Storage and Azure Signal R. It supports email and SMS (using Twilio) notification services for users. Developed using C# and Visual Studio (currently version 2022), I was the sole designer, code developer, business analyst and database architect. This software is complete and operational in the Azure Cloud. The site is https://easydmr.com. A free demo site is located at https://easydmrfree.com for evaluation.

State of Nevada

Oct 2012 - Oct 2017 (Consultant)

Application and database architect, as well as coding and server configuration for the entire Medical Marijuana program for the State of Nevada. I was the sole developer on this project. This is an ASP.NET 4.6 application developed with C#, Entity Framework 6, Bootstrap, Visual Studio 2017, SQL Server 2014 and Telerik controls. It is hosted on Microsoft Server.

This development effort involved extensive and continued interaction with staff and stake holders to understand and document the exact business requirements and workflow before development began.

The Medical Marijuana program in the State of Nevada consists of establishments (cultivation, production, laboratory and dispensary) and patients. Each establishment, agent (an establishment employee, owner, officer and board member) and patient is approved by the state. Every establishment, agent and patient is renewed on a yearly basis and every agent and patient receives an identification card (similar to a driver's license).

The Medical Marijuana web site allows individuals employed in state certified medical marijuana establishments to apply online and upload related documents (including photograph and signature). It also allows Medical Marijuana patients to apply online and tracks patient sales. I developed a method for the

patients in Nevada to take a photograph of the barcode on back of their driver's license when creating an online account. The software would read the barcode, decipher the information within and auto-populate the database, resulting in virtually zero data input errors. The patient application forms were also barcoded uniquely for each patient and type of document. This allowed the software to scan the documents that needed to be notarized and automatically and assign the documents to the correct patient. A major factor in the software design was to reduce data input error and reduce manpower through automation.

The ASP.NET Medical Marijuana application consists of four main parts: Agent Registry, Patient Registry, Patient Sales and Administration. The Registry sections are where applications are submitted and payment is accepted. The Administration section is where State staff approve applications, manage card printing, track applications, generate reports, etc. Reporting is done through SSRS (including embedding SSRS reports within the ASP.NET application).

I have also upgraded an existing ASP.NET application with additional features and security enhancements. This was a public facing site that managed services for NEIS (Nevada Early Intervention Services). This was a SQL Server 2008R2 database.

Created a new ASP.NET application for managing the SeniorRx (providing seniors with prescription and dental assistance) program. This was developed in C# with Entity Framework and used Foundation (CSS framework) as well as Telerik controls. Database services were through a SQL Server 2012 database. I designed the application, database schema, gathered requirements, made recommendations and determined exact business requirements.

Data transformations, uploading text files to the database, extracting data to text files for download, SSIS packages, C# coding for data uploading and downloading, saving and reading text and XML files.

Dental Investment Group

Oct 2010 - Mar 2012 (Consultant)

Dental office software developed using WPF and SQL Server that provides support for billing, collections, treatments plans, insurance payments, patient scheduling, inventory tracking and ordering, clinical information and financial status of practice (revenue, profits, profit by procedure, costs, etc.). This is a product set to be marketed.

St Francis Career College

Lynwood, CA

Aug 2010 - Nov 2010 (Consultant)

I developed a data-analysis software application for statistical analysis of student data designed to meet federal reporting requirements. The application was developed using WPF, C#, LINQ with SQL Server as the database. I used Visual Studio 2010, Microsoft Expressions Blend 4 and Telerik WPF controls. I wrote stored procedures to support the application. Reports were also developed in Crystal Reports.

Alcone Marketing

Irvine, CA

Jul 2010 - Sep 2010 (Kforce)

I developed browser-based reporting capability for an LG Electronics cellular phone recycling web site. I used ASP.NET, LINQ, CSS, VB.NET and jQuery to develop pre-built reports as well as an ad hoc query screen where users could select both criteria and report columns.

Gardena Memorial Hospital

Jun 2009 - Jan 2011 (Consultant)

I developed a browser (ASP.NET) application to track actual labor hours versus industry standard labor hours on a daily basis across all hospital departments with multiple layers of reporting.

Guy Guzman Page 2 of 4

Tehachapi Valley Healthcare District

May 2005 - Jul 2008 (Consultant)

Spent one year restructuring and reorganizing the hospital's IT department. This included adding new servers, installing Microsoft Exchange, documenting the network, adding security, ensuring data backups, documenting processes, establishing VPN connectivity, adding network hardware and more similar tasks,

I developed two desktop applications using some combination VB.NET, C#, LINQ, Windows Forms, WPF and Telerik controls. I gathered business requirements with analysis and documentation for the design of applications providing integrated views of multiple medical data sources including laboratory, medical records, radiology and demographics.

I architected a SQL Server database for integration of data from multiple legacy sources using SSIS and custom code.

I developed a data warehouse (fact and dimension tables) of medical and financial information using SSIS (2008) and T-SQL. Using this data warehouse as a source, I developed OLAP capabilities using SSAS (2008) with Excel pivot-tables as front-ends to the OLAP cubes.

Weyerhaeuser Realty Investors (WRI)

Seattle, WA

Apr 1989 - Dec 2004 (Consultant)

Database Architect and Systems Analyst

I was engaged in a central role for the company as a data systems analyst concerned with enterprise strategy, requirements gathering, analysis and documentation. In addition to architecting solutions, I also performed system analysis, offered technological solutions, kept abreast of new technology (software and hardware) and provided overall direction for the company from an IT perspective.

This subsidiary of Weyerhaeuser is a financial services company brings together large investors for equity and second-trust-deed financing for home developers. I developed their first database program in 1996 using Microsoft Access. This allowed the company to regularly consolidate financial information about equity and debt residential housing portfolios from Excel workbooks and JD Edwards into a database to perform forecasts looking as far as 10 years forward. The scope of this program continually evolved to include income statements, balance sheets, ROI and breakdowns by investor. This program was moved into a .NET and SQL Server environment using VB.NET in 2003.

In moving to the .NET environment, I worked with the business groups to understand business processes, information flow between business processes and the overall enterprise strategy. I also gathered and documented workflow within and between business units. I documented these processes and generated a Functional Specification and a SRS (Software Requirements Specification).

In 2003, I architected a data warehouse and OLAP solution using SQL Server technologies. This integrated data from a JD Edwards accounting system, mortgage tracking software and financial analysts Excel workbooks. Excel pivot-tables and a browser-solution were used as interfaces into the OLAP system.

I served as the technical team lead for .NET software development as well as the data warehouse and OLAP project. Other members included staff from Weyerhaeuser Corporate IT and consultants from Wipro (India).

Education

University of Notre Dame

Notre Dame, IN

Physics, M.S.

Loyola Marymount University

Los Angeles, CA

Physics, B.S.

Guy Guzman Page 3 of 4

Skill Set

Technical

- Microsoft C# (14 years)
- Microsoft VB.NET (4 years)
- Microsoft .NET thru .NET Core 6
- Microsoft ASP.NET (16 years)
- Microsoft Visual Studio (20 years)
- Microsoft Entity Framework (10 years)
- Microsoft LINQ (10 years)
- Microsoft WPF (2 years)
- JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap and jQuery
- Microsoft SQL Server (20 years)
- Microsoft SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) (10 years)
- Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS) (10 years)
- Microsoft SQL Server DBA Tasks including Security, Stored Procedures, Query Optimization
- Microsoft T-SQL
- Microsoft TFS (8 years)
- Git (6 years)
- Database Architect (16 years)
- Database Applications (20 years)
- Numerous 3rd Party Controls
- Adobe Photoshop (used whenever images are required)
- Adobe Illustrator (used whenever vector art is required)
- Adobe Premiere (used for demo videos for EasyDMR)
- Adobe After Effects (used for demo videos for EasyDMR)
- Adobe Audition (used for demo videos for EasyDMR)
- Toad (Data Modeler)

Business and Project Related

- Requirements Gathering, Analysis and Documentation
- Project Documentation (Functional Specification, Software Requirements Specification)
- Enterprise Data Analysis
- Business Process Flow Analysis and Documentation
- Excellent Written, Verbal and Interpersonal Skills
- Experience with Health Care and Financial Systems

Guy Guzman Page 4 of 4